#### Contact

zaswet@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/aleksandr-vasiljev-320210247 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

jQuery

Elementor

WooCommerce

### Languages

English (Professional Working)
Russian (Native or Bilingual)
Lithuanian (Native or Bilingual)

# Aleksandr Vasiljev

Junior Web Developer at Artix.lt

Vilnius, Vilniaus, Lithuania

## Summary

Hello there, My name is Aleksandr. i am professional cook with over 15 year's of experience. Worked in different positions, starting from line cook to a restaurant Chef. After all those years have decided to change profession, and just finished my studies of PHP and Laravel at BIT (Baltic Institute of Technology).

## Experience

Artix.It

Junior Web Developer

December 2022 - Present (1 year 11 months)

Vilnius, Vilniaus, Lithuania

Junior web developer . PHP, Wordpress , Elementor, HTML, CSS, JS, jQuery.

UAB Kitokia virtuve. Cafe Montmartre

Cook

January 2020 - March 2022 (2 years 3 months)

Vilnius, Vilniaus, Lithuania

French cuisine restaurant. Cooked breakfast, salads, steaks, hot dishes and deserts.

Uab amerika. Dinner map

Cook

August 2019 - December 2019 (5 months)

Vilnius, Vilniaus, Lithuania

Worked as a prep cook. Mainly worked with meat preparation. Some times around 60-80kg of raw meat a day. Helped ordering produce, and organize work for preparation part of kitchen.

UAB Atrasti receptai Paslepti Receptai

Cook

November 2018 - July 2019 (9 months)

Vilnius, Vilniaus, Lithuania

Worked as a prep cook. Fresh pasta, sauces, soups, meat, deserts.

SIA "Elegimide" Svečių namai "Skrablas" Nida-Latvija.

Cook, Chef.

May 2018 - September 2018 (5 months)

Nida, Latvia

Summer season job at Latvia's Nida as a Chef. created menu for restaurant, ordered produce. Cooking for customers.

UAB "Ozo restoranas" Grill London

Kitchen Supervisor

July 2016 - May 2018 (1 year 11 months)

Vilnius, Vilniaus, Lithuania

Worked as Production Manager in food chain restaurant Grill London.

Managed team of 12+ cooks. Ordering produce, food quality control, good hygiene practice for catering establishments control.

UAB "Atviras stalas". Sweet Root

Cook

September 2015 - January 2016 (5 months)

Vilnius, Vilniaus, Lithuania

Moved from hometown Klaipeda to Vilnius, to get this job. Unfortunately due health issues had to quit and take a small brake from working. It was a top class fine dining restaurant with 4 and 7 courses tasting menus.

MB "Putlutis". Fish and seafood restaurant Monte Cristo.

Cook, Chef Cook

May 2011 - September 2015 (4 years 5 months)

Klaipeda, Klaipėdos, Lithuania

Started as a line cook. After a year got promoted to restaurant Chef. Created menu, ordered produce, managed kitchen staff.

UAB "Baltijos Dorė". Hotel "Navalis"

Cook

July 2007 - April 2011 (3 years 10 months)

Klaipeda, Klaipėdos, Lithuania

Started as a line cook. prepared hotel breakfast, banquet snacks and dishes, deserts and sweets.

### Education

**Baltic Institute of Technology** 

Computer Programming · (May 2022 - November 2022)

Klaipeda school of tourism

Cooking and Related Culinary Arts, General · (September 2004 - June 2006)